Curriculum vitae

Jacek Abramczyk

Country United Kingdom Mobile no. +48 500 357 338

e-mail jacek.abramczyk@gmail.com

Website http://jrabramczyk.com



PROFILE

Accomplished software engineer with experience in .Net/C# since 2008. I have advanced competence in area of code optimization/performance, multi-threading, algorithms, business logic and database design. I'm very experienced with Object Oriented Programming/Design, Test Driven Development and SCRUM. I also have extensive background in full life-cycle of software development process including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance.

Currently I improve my skills in the areas of architecture design and team management. I also improve my skills in C++, F# and finance sector.

KEY SKILLS

Languages C#, SQL, JavaScript, F# (basic), C++ (basic)

Technologies ASP .Net (MVC), WCF, LINQ, BigData, Multithreading, MSMQ, jQuery, Quartz.Net

DBMS MSSQL, Oracle, ElasticSearch, MongoDB, Couchbase, SSIS

Architecture SaaS, Client-Server, SOA, Microservices, DDD(basic), Onion architecture

Principles OOP/OOD, TDD, SOLID

Patterns IoC, Lazy Loading, DI, Interceptor, Factory, Singleton, Repository, ...

CI TeamCity, Hudson/Jenkins

Team work SVN, Git, TFS, Agile, Scrum, Pair-programming

Bug tracking TFS, JIRA, VersionOne, Rally, IBM SCCD

Others EF, ReSharper, Matlab(basic), BPM Metastorm

Testing nUnit, Moq, Ninject, Windsor Castle, AutoFixture, nCrunch, Jasmine

WORK EXPERIENCE

1.2016 – Senior IT Consultant at Credit Suisse – UK London



EPE Primo project, gathering detailed information about trades, derivatives, equities and other investment banks products in the purpose of performance Monte Carlo simulation and other advanced calculations to measure risk of investments for Bank's Regulators.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Increase performance dramatically (in 2017 we will reach 10 times more trades and have the same amount of time to perform calculation)
- Multithreading, Parallel programming, Performance optimization
- Grid, Processes management to reduce CPU usage of single node

Technologies .Net 4.5, C#, TDD, Agile/Scrum, TeamCity, SVN, VS 2013, MSSQL 2012, ReSharper,

MSMQ, WCF, RhinoMock, nUnit, JIRA

8.2015 - 1.2016

Senior Software Developer at Achilles Group Limited – UK London



Improve and fix bugs in web application responsible for gathering buyers and suppliers so they can search one another.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Improve performance, mostly DB layer
- Migrate data from SQL Server into Couchbase

Technologies

SaaS, Couchbase, SQL Server, Asp.Net MVC, Multithreading, C#, SCRUM

8.2014 - 8.2015

Senior IT Contractor



SANTANDER CONSUMER BANK

Web application for employees of Santander Bank mainly helps in setting new agreements, creating new customers etc. Whole application is written in ASP.Net Web Forms, business logic is mostly done in JavaScript.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Implementation in accordance with the requirements of documentation and architect's comments
- Creating SSIS packages and follow SOA (Service Oriented Architecture) principles



TITIAN

Develop comprehensive software platform, purpose-built for the management of samples, including: compounds, biologicals, reagents. Designed to provide rest-assured sample inventory, tracking and an error-free supply chain, Software can streamline sample management workflows for maximum efficiency and in-house productivity.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Refactor design solution (code is not consistent with SOLID) and remove legacy code
- Implement new functionalities using TDD



THOMSON REUTERS

Design new solution for application responsible for logging (40-80) millions of events every week. Migrate data from SQL Server into MongoDB and ElasticSearch, compare solutions in terms of performance and data usage.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Investigate ability to migrate tens of millions records of data from SQL into NoSQL Database (ElasticSearch and MongoDB)
- Design, test, implement and deploy tool for migration
- Compare performance of SQL Server, ElasticSearch and MongoDB
- Find useful tools and libraries e.g. NEST which is .Net client for ElasticSearch
- Refactor old code to improve performance

2.2014 - 8.2014

Software Engineer at Powel sp. z o. o.



System responsible for exchange data in the Nordic energy market with focus on very secure, fast and what's more reliable way because of very sensitive information and domain usage. Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Estimate tasks including tests that are necessary to cover bigger part of code. During development we were focus on TDD and DDD
- Improving performance by parallel programming, remove legacy and 3rd party code
- Code review especially of newest and youngest employees
- Design solution (architecture, technologies, patterns)
- Extreme programming (Pair-programming), Micro-pairing

Technologies

.Net 4.5, C#, MSMQ, Ninject, nUnit, WCF, Code Contracts, Onion Architecture, TDD, DDD, Pair-programming, Parallel programming, LINQ, Oracle

8.2012 - 2.2014

.Net Developer at Atena financial and IT services S.A.



Web application for insurance adjusters to manage process of damages. System helps employees make a decision of compensate for damages when customer had an accident, loss or injury.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Estimate tasks, design and implement functionalities
- Read business documentation and write technical one
- Write documentation and requirements based on customer needs
- Maintenance old functionalities
- Design database, improve long old stored procedures and migrate them into code
- Refactor old functionalities using OOP, SOLID and TDD
- Parallel programming, lazy loading and caching data in order to improve performance
- Aspect oriented programming (AOP) for logging and try catch statements
- Direct contact with customer and business analyst

Technologies

ASP .Net 3.5, C#, JavaScript (jQuery, knockout.js), WCF, nUnit, Moq, WindsorCastle, TDD, T-SQL, MSSQL, BPM Metastorm, SVN

5.2012 - 8.2012

.Net Developer at Hakon Software sp. z o. o.



Desktop application created for dental companies which require management of patients, history of treatments and past diseases. Book future visits and create detailed plan of treatments. Many additional functionalities for dentists.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Gather requirements from dentists then design and implement functionalities
- Migrate new customer's data from different systems
- Design database and system components

Technologies

Windows Forms, C#, .Net 2.0, MVS 2008, MSSQL

2.2011 - 11.2011

Software Engineer at Smart Systems sp. z o. o.

Project created in order to make call center more efficient. Whole information of clients were stored in Microsoft Office Excel files so it was hard to looking for information, sort it, change it and what's more share it by 30 employees at the same time.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Design, Implement, Configure and Deploy whole platform from scratch
- Design database and move data from Excel files into database ensure transactions
- Design website which provide all required functionalities
- Design module that can make statistics about individual employee's results

Technologies

PHP, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Ajax, JavaScript, Windows Server 2003

2009 - 2011

Freelance projects

Projects

- 1. CMS Web MVC applications provided rent apartments and online shops functionalities.
 - C#, ASP.Net MVC, EF
- 2. Several websites for individual people, mostly 3 page websites without complicated logic. All projects were done using PHP, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL/MySQL.

CERTIFICATE

Microsoft

Course 6654: Introducing to Windows Communication Foundation

EDUCATION

2014 Master of Computer science and Mathematics, Department of Software Engineering,

Gdansk University of Technology

Main subjects:

Parallel processing CUDA/CELL

• Base analysis of capital markets

• High performance computing systems

• Advanced technology of DB

2012 Bachelor of Computer science and Mathematics, Department of Algorithms and System

Modeling, Gdansk University of Technology

Main subjects:

• Mathematical analysis and linear algebra

Algorithms and data structure

Discrete mathematics

• Numerical methods

• Probability and mathematical statistics

Physics

• Computer architecture

• Analysis of algorithms

• Artificial intelligence – MATLAB

Object oriented programming

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Algoithm www.hackerrank.com, www.spoj.pl - Looking for new solutions in algorithm problems, code

challenges optimization

Activities Chess, basketball, gym, swimming and running

Psychology Motivation, emotional intelligence

"I hereby agree for processing my personal data, included in my job offer, for the purpose of recruitment (as defined in the Act of August 29, 1997 on the Protection of Personal Data (Journal of Laws No. 133, item 883)."